A romantic comedy for anyone who's ever been dumped.
The Baxter is a comedy, romance film directed by Michael Showalter.
Mild mannered tax accountant Elliot Sherman is what he calls a "Baxter": the kind of calm, unexciting fellow who "wears
sock garters" and "enjoys raking leaves." Loved by bosses and parents, Elliot is a perfectly nice guy.
And that's his problem.
Elliot Sherman, played by Michael Showalter.
Caroline Swann, played by Elizabeth Banks.
Cecil Mills, played by Michelle Williams.
Bradley Lake, played by Justin Theroux.
Wendall Wimms, played by Zak Orth.
Ed, played by Michael Ian Black.
The Baxter is a 2005 American comedy film written by, directed
by and starring comedian Michael Showalter.
A "Baxter", as defined by the film, is the nice, dull guy in a romantic
comedy who is dumped at the end of the story for the protagonist.
Much light humor is made of showing Showalter as a "Baxter" in several typical romantic comedy clichés: being abandoned at the altar as a
former love is claimed by her high school sweetheart, and being left in college at a pep rally for an underdog sports hero.
The plot revolves around the life of Elliot Sherman during the two weeks before his wedding, as
he doggedly fights off the curse of his former Baxter role in relationships.
IFC Films financed the film and produced it with Plum Pictures.
They gave the film a very limited release; it had a U.S.
box office gross of $181,872.
The film explores themes of love triangle, flashback, wedding, screwball comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.